他是个好律师，大家都很喜欢他
He's a good lawyer and he's well liked
耶稣基督!
Jesus Christ!
这是门。给我两分钟。
That's the door. Give me two minutes.
我们刚听说亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯被枪杀了。
We've just heard that Alex Galbraith has been shot dead.
他的妻子很有可能成为我们的下一任议员。
There's a very good chance that his wife is going to be our next MP.
岛上的每个人都在某个时候遇到过他。
Everybody on the isles came across him at some point.
有一场监护权之争。
There was a custody battle.
妻子因为吸毒而失去了孩子。
The wife lost her kids due to drug addiction.
——琳达莫顿?-他们在问亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯的事?
- Lynda Morton? - They were asking about Alex Galbraith?
你最好别提我的名字
You better not have mentioned my name
谈话的任何部分
in any part of that conversation.
有个小问题。当地的小伙子。弗雷泽克雷根。
Got a wee problem. Local lad. Fraser Creggan.
他一直在网上发布加尔布雷斯谋杀案的消息。
He's been posting about the Galbraith killing online.
我们有洛根·克雷根。
We've got a Logan Creggan.
在我们的枪支拥有者名册上
On our register of gun owners.
唐娜·基利克的事让我很生气
I am pissed off about Donna Killick.
她杀了我妹妹，还能回家
She kills my sister, and then gets to come home
-死在自己的床上?——妈妈。
- to die in her own bed? - Mum.
你丈夫用无人机做什么?
What does your husband use the drone for?
他开着飞机在海岸上来回飞行。
He was out flying it up and down the coast.
你真的要这么做吗?
You really have to take this dive?
我有B计划。
I've got a plan B.
那是你的选择，但你会后悔的。
Well, that's your choice, but you'll regret it.
他们把他们带回来了。
They're bringing them back up.
冠军宝座。设得兰警局想和你谈谈。
Eamon. Shetland Police want to talk to you.
我们正在失去压力。
We're losing pressure.
小锚夫人吗?我是贝德福德博士
Mrs Killick? I'm Dr Bedford,
勒威克综合医院的顾问。
Consultant at Lerwick General.
这是梅格·帕蒂森护士。
This is Nurse Meg Pattison.
欢迎回到设得兰群岛。
Welcome back to Shetland.
正确的。我们该走了。
Right. We should get going.
你好的。
You OK.
他怎么了?
What happened to him?
埃蒙的减压器出了点问题。
There was a problem with Eamon's decompression.
耶稣。
Jesus.
如果那个房间爆炸了……
If that chamber blew...
他会很痛苦的。
he would have been in so much pain.
柯斯蒂，我知道这很难…
Kirsty, I know this is hard, erm...
我要问你几个问题。
I'm going to have to ask you a few questions.
在埃蒙去上班之前，他怎么样?
Before Eamon left to go to work, how was he?
这是他第一次情绪这么好。
For once he was in good spirits.
他走之前说什么了吗?
Did he say anything before he left?
他说他有备用计划。
He said he had a plan B.
你知道他是什么意思吗?
Do you know what he meant by that?
我不知道。
I've no idea.
你会知道发生了什么事?
You'll find out what happened?
我会尽我所能。
I'll do everything I can.
她只是停靠。
She's just docked.
这是康纳·麦凯。康纳被任命的
This is Connor McKay. Connor's been appointed
由工业安全管理局调查事故。
by the Industrial Safety Authority to investigate the accident.
很明显，这事由你们来主导，
Obviously, you guys are going to take the lead on this,
但高迪是一起谋杀案的潜在证人。
but Gauldie was a potential witness in a murder investigation.
所以我希望，你知道，我们可以合作。
So I'm hoping that, you know, we could work together.
当然可以。你会第一个看到我们的发现。
Of course. You'll be the first to see our findings.
是的,你看,
Yeah, you see,
我真不想坐着等着看报告。
I don't really want to sit about and wait to read a report.
我要进入事故现场
I want access to the accident scene
还有所有的证据。
and all the evidence.
-财政部门必须澄清这一点。——啊。她已经有了。
- Fiscal will have to clear that. - Aye. She already has.
好的。
OK.
财政部门批准了吗?
Has the Fiscal cleared it?
不。所以我需要你打电话给她。
No. That's why I need you to call her.
大部分船员都被撤职了。
Most of the crew's been stood down.
每个人都还在震惊中。
Everyone's still in shock.
我整理了一份事故的录像给你看。
I've lined up a recording of the accident for you to view.
8点20分，埃蒙转移到一个单独的空房间。
At 8:20, Eamon transfers in to a separate unoccupied chamber.
在他转院18分钟后
18 minutes after he transferred,
压力大幅下降。
there's a massive drop in pressure.
外部阀门的破裂。
A breach of an external valve.
我们试着把它从这里分离出来，但它没有反应。
We tried to isolate it from in here but it wouldn't respond.
谁是负责潜水员的生命支持主管?
Who was the Life Support Supervisor responsible for the divers?
我。和米克·穆尔。
Me. And Mick Muir.
米克在他的小屋里。他感觉不舒服。
Mick's in his cabin. He's not feeling well.
我让米克去手动关闭外部阀门，但是…
I sent Mick out to try and close the external valve manually but...
但他没能及时赶到。
But he didn't make it in time.
是什么造成了缺口?
What caused the breach?
阀门一定是松了，造成了泄漏。
The valve must have came loose which caused a leak.
它为什么松了?
Why did it come loose?
我们不知道。
We don't know.
我们做了所有的潜水前检查，一切都很安全。
We did all the pre-dive checks and everything was secure.
你检查过了吗?
Did you do the checks?
米克把他们抬了出去。
Mick carried them out.
弄松有多容易?
How easy is it to loosen that?
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
我的意思是，
Well, what I mean is,
会不会是有人进来用手把它解开的?
could someone have come in here and loosened it by hand?
是啊，但他们为什么要这么做?
Well, aye, but why would they?
你认为这是故意的吗?
Do you think this was deliberate?
高迪是最接近目击证人的人
Gauldie was the closest thing we had to a witness
我们还没来得及跟他说话他就死了。
and he dies minutes before we're due to speak to him.
去设得兰的加尔布雷斯是一回事，
Getting to Galbraith in Shetland is one thing,
但凶手是怎么上船去杀高迪的?
but how did the killer get on board to kill Gauldie?
可能不止一个凶手?
Could be more than one killer?
杀了加尔布雷斯的人找了别人去杀高迪。
Whoever killed Galbraith got someone else to kill Gauldie.
在船上工作的人。
Somebody who works on the ship.
那我们说的就是有关系，有钱，有资源的人。
Then we're talking about someone with connections, money, resources.
跟所有能进入潜水室的人谈谈
Talk to everybody who had access to the dive chamber
但先从米克·缪尔开始。
but start with Mick Muir.
好的。
OK.
很容易。
Nice and easy.
能帮帮忙吗?
Any chance of some help?
我接到的命令是护送她回家。
My orders were to escort her to the house.
我所做的。
I've done that.
嘿。
Hey.
你到底是怎么了?
What the hell is wrong with you?
这位女士的癌症已经到了第四阶段。
The woman has stage four cancer.
-你对她了解多少?-我知道她快死了
- What do you know about her? - I know that she's dying.
她需要一点同情。
And she could do with a bit of compassion.
这是多娜小锚。
That's Donna Killick.
她杀了一个18岁的女孩，我的一个朋友，
She murdered an 18-year-old girl, a friend of mine,
然后她让一个无辜的人坐了20年牢
and then she let an innocent man spend 20 years in jail
为她的罪行。
for her crime.
我有足够的同情心……
I've got plenty of compassion...
但对她来说并非如此。
but not for her.
潜水前我检查了所有的阀门。
I checked all the valves before the dive.
他们每个人都很安全。
Every one of them was secure.
-那是什么造成的?-我不知道。
- So then, what caused the breach? - I don't know.
这不是会发生的事。
It's not something that happens.
永远。
Ever.
可能是密封坏了，或者阀门出了故障。
Maybe the seal broke or the valve malfunctioned.
或者是有人手动解开的?
Or maybe someone loosened it manually?
好吧，那不是我。
Well, it wasnae me.
拉森告诉你是我了吗?
Did Larson tell you it was me?
因为你要知道我和他合不来。
Because you need to know me and him don't get on.
你和高迪处得好吗?
Did you and Gauldie get on?
我和埃蒙没有问题。
I had no problem with Eamon.
其他船员呢?他们和他有过节吗?
What about the rest of the crew? Any of them have issues with him?
不。他很讨人喜欢。
No. He was pretty well liked.
你没见过他和别人吵架吗?
You never saw him arguing with anyone?
他进密室的前一晚，
The night before he got in the chamber,
我听到他在电话里跟人诉苦。
I heard him giving somebody grief over the phone.
他说是他妻子。我从来不相信他。
He said it was his wife. I never believed him.
-你为什么不相信他?-我不知道。
- Why didn't you believe him? - I don't know.
他只是听起来像在和他妻子说话。
He just didnae sound like he was talking to his wife.
如果埃蒙有什么问题
If Eamon had a problem,
他会和谁说话?
who would he talk to?
也许是凯莉·麦克安德鲁。
Err, Carrie McAndrew maybe.
她是厨师。她和埃蒙是好朋友。
She's the chef. Her and Eamon were pally.
正确的。
Right.
凯特。这是桑迪。
Kate. It's Sandy.
她是今天早上到的。
She arrived this morning.
我想你会想知道。
I thought you'd want to know.
有空给我打电话。好吗?
Call me when you can. OK?
你和唐娜·基利克谈得怎么样?
How did it get on with Donna Killick?
我刚把她送到她家。
I just dropped her off at her house.
-她怎么样?——她很好。
- And how was she? - She's fine.
有个医生和护士跟在她后面
She's got a doctor and a nurse running around after her
就像她是什么名人一样。
like she's some sort of celebrity.
正确的。
Right.
找到高迪的无人机了吗?
Any luck finding Gauldie's drone?
还没有。
Not yet.
但技术人员认为我们应该找的是SD卡
But the tech boys reckon it's the SD card we should be looking for
而不是无人机。
and not the drone.
卡片是存储数据的地方
The card is where the data is stored
埃蒙可能在无人机被偷之前就把它拿走了。
and Eamon may have taken it out before the drone was stolen.
好的。跟柯斯蒂·高迪谈谈看她知不知道它在哪。
OK. Well talk to Kirsty Gauldie and see if she knows where it is.
啊。吉米,
Ah. Jimmy,
刚接到因弗内斯媒体官员的电话。
just had a call from the media officer in Inverness.
基尔缪尔的犯罪现场照片引起了轩然大波。
Those Kilmuir crime scene photos are causing a big stooshie.
唐尼查出是谁发的原始照片了吗?
Has Donnie worked out who posted the original images?
他说他正在努力。
Says he's working on it.
所以,很明显,
So, apparently,
我今早授权进入一个事故现场。
I authorised access to an accident scene this morning.
问题是，我不记得做过。
Thing is, I don't remember doing it.
事实上，我甚至不记得有人提过要求。
In fact, I don't even remember someone making a request.
我们试过给你打电话。
Well, we tried to call you.
哦,好吧。至少你试过了。
Oh, well. Least you tried.
我得上那艘船。我们没有时间等了。
I needed to get on that ship. We didn't have time to wait.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
康纳·麦凯说你认为高迪是被谋杀的。
Connor McKay says you think Gauldie was murdered.
如果戴高迪目击了加尔布雷斯被杀
If Gauldie witnessed Galbraith's murder,
也许凶手在他开口之前就杀了他。
then maybe the shooter got to him before he could talk.
在北海的中央?
In the middle of the North Sea?
我们正在研究一个理论
We're working on a theory that
枪手派人在船上下手。
the shooter got someone on board the ship to do it.
这提醒了我。桑迪，盯着琳达·莫顿。
Which reminds me. Sandy, keep an eye on Lynda Morton.
我想知道最近有谁来看过她。
I want to know who's been visiting her recently.
对不起,琳达莫顿?
Sorry, Lynda Morton?
琳达的前夫是加尔布雷斯的客户。
Lynda's ex-husband was a client of Galbraith's.
加尔布雷斯的笔记,
In Galbraith's notes,
他指控琳达与毒贩勾结。
he accused Lynda of associating with drug dealers.
对不起。比利…
Sorry. Billy...
我需要最近每一起毒品逮捕案的细节。
I need the details of every recent drug arrest.
与大陆黑帮有联系的毒贩。
Dealers linked with mainland gangs.
如果加尔布雷斯是对的，
If Galbraith was right,
琳达和一些严重的罪犯混在一起。
then Lynda was mixing with some serious criminals.
加尔布雷斯不是谋杀。
Galbraith wasn't murdered.
他被暗杀。
He was assassinated.
他们用的是无法追踪的枪。
They used an untraceable gun.
他们使用幽灵子弹。
They used ghost bullets.
所有这些都需要资源和组织，
Now all of that takes resources and organisation,
这正是你想要的
which is exactly what you want
如果你想在海上杀死目击证人。
if you're looking to kill a witness at sea.
下次，你等着我回答。
Next time, you wait for an answer.
理解。
Understood.
琳达莫顿?
Lynda Morton?
我已经告诉你的同事了
I already told your colleague,
我不知道亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯怎么了。
I don't know what happened to Alex Galbraith.
好的。埃蒙·高迪呢?
OK. What about Eamon Gauldie?
谁?
Who?
你吸毒有多久了?
How long have you had a drug problem for?
我出了车祸。
I was in a car crash.
两年前。
Two years ago.
我的腿受伤了，所以他们给我吃了止痛药。
My leg got smashed up so they put me on painkillers.
那些真的很好的。
The really good ones.
不知不觉间，我一天都离不开它们。
Before I knew it, I couldn't get through the day without them.
然后我变得很沮丧。和…
Then I got depressed. And...
而不是问我是否需要帮助，我的前任只是…
instead of asking me if I needed any help, my ex just...
以此为借口甩了我，带走了我的孩子们。
used it as an excuse to dump me and take my boys.
现在我只有那些药了。
Now all I have are the pills.
这让我想到了你们的经销商。
Which brings me to your dealers.
我没有毒贩。
I don't have dealers.
亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯认为你做到了。
Alex Galbraith thought you did.
他的证据。
He had evidence.
当然，我们不知道证据是什么，
Of course, we don't know what that evidence was,
因为他家里的文件被偷了。
because the file was stolen from his house.
是啊，那跟我一点关系都没有。
Yeah, and that was nothing to do with me.
也许不是你偷的
Maybe you didn't steal it,
但我打赌你知道是谁干的
but I'm betting that you know who did.
我知道你很害怕。我知道。但你的这些朋友
I know you're scared. I know. But these friends of yours,
他们可能不仅仅是破门而入。
they might have done more than just break into a house.
如果你告诉我他们的名字，我就能保护你。
So if you give me their names, then I can protect you.
我需要你离开。
I need you to leave.
那是等你改变主意时用的。
That's for when you change your mind.
我要把它搬出公寓。
I want it out of the flat.
我们已经谈过了。
We've been through this.
没有，警察又来了。那家伙佩雷斯。
No, the police were round again. That guy Perez.
他问的是…
And he was asking about...
他在问加尔布雷斯家被闯入的事。
He was asking about the break-in at Galbraith's house.
如果他回来搜查那地方怎么办?
What if he comes back and searches the place?
这不是我的错，我不会进监狱的。
I can't take the blame for this, OK, I'm not going to prison.
耶稣。你能冷静一下吗?
Jesus. Will you calm down?
给我点时间再找个地方。
Give me some time to sort another place.
回家了。在那儿等我。
Go home. Wait for me there.
别担心。
Don't worry.
就好了。
It'll be OK.
这是过去六个月里所有重要的毒品逮捕记录。
That's every significant drugs arrest in the last six months.
米克·穆尔。你听说过他吗?
Mick Muir. You heard of him?
不，不记得了。他是谁?
No, doesnae ring a bell. Who is he?
可能就是他造成了埃蒙·高迪所谓的意外。
Could be he's the guy who caused Eamon Gauldie's supposed accident.
调查一下他的背景
Do a background check on him.
看看他和我们要找的人有没有关系
See if he's linked to anybody that we're looking at
-在加尔布雷斯的案子里——好的,当然。
- in the Galbraith case. - OK, sure.
邓肯?
Duncan?
你告诉你爸爸你今天带他去吃午饭了吗?
Did you tell your Dad that you'd take him for lunch today?
什么?不。
What? No.
为什么?他说了什么?
Why? What's he saying?
你今天要带他去吃午饭。
That you're taking him for lunch today.
在斯卡洛威旅馆。
At The Scalloway Hotel.
是在斯卡洛威旅馆。
At The Scalloway Hotel, no less.
不…不。他很困惑。
No... no. He's confused.
呃…
Er...
把他。
put him on.
吉米?
Jimmy?
你在哪里?我等待。
Where are you? I'm waiting.
爸爸。我从没说过我们今天要出去吃午饭。
Dad. I never said that we were going to go out and have lunch today.
什么?
What?
我从没说过我们要去吃午饭。
I-I never said that we were going to go and have lunch.
我在工作中。我走不开。
I'm at work. I can't get away.
爸爸?
Dad?
它,是我。
It, it's me.
我从没说过要带他出去。
I never said that I was going to take him out.
我不知道他从哪学来的。
Er, I don't know where he's got that from.
对了,听。没事的。我要把它咬一口
Right, listen. It's, it's all right. I'll take him for a bite
在城市的某个地方。就大。
in town somewhere. It'll be grand.
-你确定吗?——啊,啊。确定。
- Are you sure? - Aye, aye. Sure.
好的。谢谢,邓肯。
OK. Thanks, Duncan.
一切都好吧?
Everything all right?
很好。是什么问题?
Fine. What's the problem?
你要的加尔布雷斯时间线。
The Galbraith timeline you asked for.
有三个小时的时间
There's a three-hour window
就在他被枪击的前一天，我们无法解释。
in the day before he was shot that we can't account for.
你跟菲奥娜·贝德福德谈过了吗?
You speak to Fiona Bedford?
她也不知道他在做什么。
She has no idea what he was doing either.
他似乎在1点到4点之间消失了。
Seems he dropped off the radar between one and four o'clock.
好吧。我会和伊芙谈谈。
All right. I'll speak to Eve.
一种药物?
A drug hit?
你是认真的吗?
Are you serious?
我们正在跟进这件事。
It's something we're following up on.
亚历克斯跟你提过毒品的事吗?
Did Alex ever mention anything about drugs to you?
不，我不记得了。
No, not that I remember.
我应该担心吗?我应该……
Should I be worried? Should I...
我该把莫兰带出这房子吗?
should I be getting Merran out of this house?
你的保护人员来了。
Your protection officers are here.
但如果你想的话，我可以安排一个安全屋。
But I can arrange a safe house if that's what you want.
不…不，让她回家已经够难的了。
No... No, it was hard enough getting her to come home.
如果……如果我们再走，她会寸步不离的。
If... if we leave again, she'll dig her heels in.
他们来了。我能出去吗?
The guys are here. Can I go out?
我宁愿你跟我在一起。
I'd rather you stayed close.
我们正要去海滩。
We're just going down to the beach.
好的。保持联系，莫兰。
OK. Just keep in touch, Merran.
你走之前还有一件事。
Er, just one thing before you go.
有件事我想问你和你妈妈。
There was something that I wanted to ask you and your mum.
我们无法确定你父亲的下落
We're having trouble accounting for your Dad's whereabouts
就在他死的前一天
on the day before he died.
你们俩谁都知道
Either of you have any idea
下午他在哪里?
where he was during the afternoon?
他没在上班?
He wasn't at work?
菲奥娜·贝德福德说没有。
Fiona Bedford says no.
Merran吗?
Merran?
我在学校。
I was at school.
你爸爸有没有提到他那天在做什么?
Did your Dad happen to mention what he was doing that day?
他什么也没说。
He never said anything.
我能感觉到她在抽离。
I can feel her pulling away.
我相信她准备好了就会说的。
I'm sure she'll talk when she's ready.
我今天下午会安排转账。
I'll set up the transfer this afternoon.
不，不，没关系。
No, no, that's all right.
听着，我知道创业有多难。
Listen, I know how hard it is to set up a business.
爱夏。
Love to Rasha.
呃，一切还好吧?
Is, er, everything all right?
你是尼文·格思里吗?
Are you Niven Guthrie?
看不见你。
Aye.
我想跟伊芙说几句话。
Yeah, I'd just like to have a quick word with Eve.
你觉得她怎么样?
How does she seem to you?
就像刚刚失去丈夫的人。
Like somebody who just lost her husband.
看不见你。
Aye.
她需要分散一下注意力
Well, she needs a distraction.
能让她转移注意力的东西。
Something to take her mind off things.
所以我觉得她应该退出竞选。
That's why I think she should be back out campaigning.
你似乎对这次竞选很有影响力。
You seem to be throwing a lot of weight behind this campaign.
我只是想帮忙。
I'm just helping out.
是啊，不止这些。你资助她。
Aye, it's more than that. You're funding her.
我对伊芙很有信心。
Look, I have a lot of faith in Eve.
你知道，我觉得她可以帮助这些岛屿。
And, you know, I think she can help the islands.
你有什么好处?
And what's in it for you?
改变世界的机会?
The chance to make a difference?
大多数潜水员都很痛苦。认为他们比我们强。
Most divers are a pain. Think they're better than us.
但不是冠军宝座。
But not Eamon.
他是个好人。好开心。
He was a nice guy. Good laugh.
你最后一次和他说话是什么时候?
When did you last talk to him?
他刚到这里来吃早饭，就进了房间。
He came in here for breakfast just before he went into the chamber.
你没看到他在房间里吗?
You didn't see him in the chamber?
拉森说厨房的工作人员可以进入卫星控制中心。
Er, Larson said that the galley staff have access to Sat Control.
我通常在6点左右吃晚饭，
I normally take up the evening meal at about six,
但米克昨晚来取了
but Mick came and picked it up last night.
-米克·缪尔?——啊。
- Mick Muir? - Aye.
他昨晚怎么样?
How was he last night?
看起来很好。
Seemed fine.
他把自己锁在船舱里了。
He's locked himself in his cabin.
这可能是件好事。
Well, that might be a good thing.
谣传是米克造成了埃蒙的事故。
The rumour is Mick caused Eamon's accident.
你已经失去控制了，是吗?
Gone analogue, have you?
警察拿走了我的电脑。
Well, the police took my desktop away.
是的，我们还在查。
Yeah, we're still going through it.
你知道这次泄密可能是内鬼干的吧?
You do realise this leak of yours was probably an inside job?
真的吗?你知道些什么吗?
Really? You know something about it?
我只是说，就算我也没蠢到黑进警察的电脑。
I'm just saying, even I'm not stupid enough to hack a police computer.
废话吗?
Tosh?
米克·缪尔被袭击了。
Mick Muir's been attacked.
他在去勒威克综合医院的路上。
He's on his way to Lerwick General.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
他在自己的船舱里被袭击了。
He was assaulted in his cabin.
胡说。他在做什么?
Tosh. How's he doing?
他要做手术了。他手臂上有几处骨折。
He's going into surgery. He's got a couple of fractures in his arm.
-他说谁袭击他了吗?-他说他没看见。
- Did he say who attacked him? - He says he didn't see them.
原谅我。DI佩雷斯。设得兰群岛警察。
Excuse me. DI Perez. Shetland Police.
哦,基督。我告诉你。
Oh, Christ. I told you.
我被伏击。我没看见是谁干的。
I was ambushed. I didn't see who did it.
但你知道他们为什么这么做。
But you know why they did it.
我和埃蒙的死一点关系都没有。我做了我的工作，仅此而已。
I had nothing to do with Eamon's death. I did my job, that's all.
你的队友不同意。
Your crewmates disagree.
我被陷害了。
I'm being set up.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
我不知道。
I don't know.
我可以收买他，因为他玩忽职守。
I can buy him causing it through negligence.
但我不能让他那样杀高迪。
But I can't see him killing Gauldie like that.
我看不出动机。
And I can't see a motive.
也许我们只是还没找到而已。
Maybe we just haven't found it yet.
我们得把缪尔和加尔布雷斯联系起来。
We have to link Muir to Galbraith.
所以找出他们之间的联系。他住在哪里?
So find out what connects them. Where does he live?
他在布雷有一处漏气了。
He's got a flat in Brae.
我去和基恩谈谈看看能不能拿到搜查令。
I'll speak to Kean and see if we can get a search warrant.
唐尼有东西给我们。
Donnie's got something for us.
我翻了弗雷泽的桌面。
I went through Fraser's desktop.
上面有些奇怪的东西。谁看尸检视频是为了好玩?
Some right weird stuff on it. Who watches autopsy videos for fun?
唐尼吗?
Donnie?
哦,对不起。不管怎么说,呃,
Oh, sorry. Anyway, er,
弗雷泽没有黑进你的数据库。
Fraser didn't hack into your database.
事实上，据我所知，没有人这么做。
In fact, as far as I can see, nobody did.
你是说内鬼?
You mean an inside job?
这就是我的想法，是的。
That would be my thinking, aye.
我们能确定是谁在内部下载的吗?
So can we identify who downloaded these internally?
他们没有下载。
They weren't downloaded.
不，我觉得是发给《纪事报》的照片
No, I think the images sent to The Chronicle
从原件中扫描出来的
were scanned from the originals.
我是说，作为一种借口，这很粗糙，但很有效。
I mean, as a piece of subterfuge, it's crude, but it's effective.
没有任何数字痕迹。
There's no digital traces whatsoever.
他似乎不太高兴。
He doesn't seem very happy.
不要往心里去。
Don't take it personally.
先生!
Sir!
我不管唐尼怎么说
I don't care what Donnie says,
我觉得这里没人会向媒体泄密。
I don't believe anyone in here would leak to the press.
不,我没有。
No, me neither.
犯罪现场的原始图像保存在停尸房。
The original crime scene images are stored at the mortuary.
给柯拉打电话，告诉她
Call Cora and tell her
泄密者可能来自她的部门。
the leak might have come from her department.
告诉她我们需要一份所有人的名单
And tell her we're going to need a list of all the people
-谁能看到照片——正确的。
- who've got access to the images. - Right.
高迪家的搜索小组
So, the search team at the Gauldie house
没找到埃蒙无人机的SD卡。
didn't find the SD card for Eamon's drone.
但柯斯蒂表示，他是在休息时间剪辑视频的。
But Kirsty says he edited the videos on his breaks.
他觉得他可能带着它去上班了。
Thinks he might have taken it to his work with him.
所以情报管理局可能有。
So the ISA might have it.
我晚点可以去他们的实验室。
I could head over to their lab later on.
好的。好。琳达·莫顿有什么消息?
OK. Good. What's the word on Lynda Morton?
她公寓外有辆巡逻车。
Er, we got a patrol car outside her flat.
她大约两点钟回家。一个人。没有访客的迹象。
She came home about two. Alone. No sign of any visitors.
好的。我要你今晚过去，看看谁会出现。
OK. I want you over there tonight, and see who turns up.
我得出去一个小时。
I've got to go out for an hour.
好的。一切都好吗?
OK. Is everything all right?
是的。我要找的人。
Yeah. Someone I need to talk to.
今天早些时候,
Earlier today,
我问你知不知道你爸爸在哪里
When I asked if you knew where your Dad was
他死的前一天
the day before he died,
我觉得你知道的比你说的要多。
I got the feeling that you knew more than you were letting on.
我知道你和你爸爸关系很好。
I know that you and your Dad were close.
我知道你想保护他。
And I know that you want to protect him.
我不知道他在哪里。好吗?
I don't know where he was. OK?
你觉得他在哪里?
Where do you think he was?
可能和她在一起。
Probably with her.
会是谁呢?
And who would that be?
菌群。
Flora.
植物M。
Flora M.
植物M ?
Flora M?
那是她打电话时他手机上出现的名字。
That was the name that came up on his phone when she rang.
你怎么知道她和你爸爸是…?
And how do you know that she and your Dad were...?
我注意到的东西。
I noticed things.
我妈妈没有的东西。
Things my mum didn't.
她一打电话，他就鬼鬼祟祟的。
When she called, he'd get all secretive.
他会去另一个房间和她说话。
He'd go off into another room to talk to her.
之后，他的脸上总是带着内疚的表情。
And afterwards, he'd always have this guilty look on his face.
这个弗洛拉·M在他死的前一天打过电话吗?
Did this Flora M call the day before he died?
当我们要去学校的时候。
As we were leaving for school.
你确定是她吗
And you're sure it was her?
它是她的。
It was her.
我们还在查加尔布雷斯的联系人。
We're still going through Galbraith's contacts.
但到目前为止，我们还没有遇到弗洛拉。
But so far, we haven't come across a Flora.
如果他有外遇，他很可能会隐瞒得很好。
If he was having an affair, he'd probably have kept it well-hidden.
是啊，尤其是伊芙要竞选议员。
Yeah, especially with Eve running to be an MP.
他需要格外小心。
He'd need to be extra careful.
比利，再查一遍加尔布雷斯的通话记录
Billy, go through Galbraith's phone records again
看看能不能找到莫兰提到的那通电话
and see if you can find the call that Merran mentioned.
有人回复你了吗
Did anybody get back to you
对洛根·克雷根的调查
on the IHAT investigation into Logan Creggan?
克雷根和他的部队被指控在伊拉克虐囚。
It seems Creggan and his unit were accused of prisoner abuse in Iraq.
很多情况下。这是一起死亡事件。
Lots of cases. One that involved a fatality.
那么为什么指控被撤销了呢?
So why were the charges dropped?
他们没有。
They weren't.
但政府在2017年停止了IHAT。
But the government pulled the plug on IHAT in 2017.
你还好吗?
Are you OK?
我的律师中枪了，
I've got a lawyer who was shot,
我有个目击证人被以最可怕的方式杀害了。
I've got a witness who was killed in the most horrific way imaginable.
我有多个嫌疑人和作案动机
I've got multiple suspects and motives,
我没有任何线索能将他们联系起来
and I've got nothing to connect any of them.
最重要的是，
And to top it all off,
有人把犯罪现场照片泄露给了媒体。
I've got somebody leaking crime scene photos to the press.
所以，不，不是真的。
So no, not really.
我个人的意思。
I meant personally.
我知道。
I know.
谢谢你的关心，但从这方面来说，我没事。
And thanks for asking, but on that front, I'm fine.
记住你这几天过得很艰难。
Just remember you've had a tough few days.
你需要放松。
You need to take it easy.
我不能,胡说。我要去出诊了
I can't, Tosh. I've got a house call to make
我的另一个问题-
to the other problem I've got -
多娜小锚。
Donna Killick.
嗨。我是迪佩雷斯。设得兰群岛警察。
Hi. I'm DI Perez. Shetland Police.
对不起。进来。
Sorry. Come in.
一次又一次。
And again.
来欢迎我回家?
Here to welcome me home?
我只是来看看你安顿好了没有
I'm just here to see if you've settled in
如果你还需要什么。
and if there's anything else you need.
你还能再活十年?
You got another ten years?
我想你听说了亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯的事。
I take it you heard about Alex Galbraith.
我们不知道他的死和你的审判有没有关系
We don't know if his death had anything to do with your trial,
或者释放你，但这是可能的。
or your release, but it is possible.
你为什么要告诉我?
And why are you telling me?
如果他被杀是因为救了你出狱，
Well, if he was killed because he got you out of prison,
我以为你会觉得自己有责任。
I thought you might feel some kind of responsibility.
我觉得我有很多责任。
I feel responsible for a lot of things.
但不是他的死
But not his death.
我不喜欢你试图让我觉得我应该。
And I don't appreciate you trying to make me feel that I should.
亚历克斯是个好人。
Alex was a good man.
这是一件可怕的事情。
It was an awful thing to happen.
达伦·贝德福德。勒威克综合医院的顾问。
Darren Bedford. Consultant at Lerwick General.
贝德福德?
Bedford?
我的妻子，菲奥娜。她是亚历克斯的私人助理。
Ah, my wife, Fiona. She was Alex's PA.
我知道艾丽克丝为了救你付出了多少努力，唐娜。
So I knew how hard Alex worked to secure your release, Donna.
他所做的一切不仅是为了别人，也是为了自己。
He did what he did as much for himself as anyone else.
他太喜欢拍自己的背了。
He liked to pat himself on the back just a bit too much.
有点像我们的吉米。
A bit like our Jimmy.
明天再见。
I'll see you again tomorrow.
你知道的…
You know...
一会儿,
for a minute,
我还以为你是来道歉的。
I thought you might be here to apologise.
为什么道歉?
To apologise for what?
在我的审判中撒谎。
Lying at my trial.
也许说谎有点残酷
Well, maybe lying's a bit harsh,
但你肯定没说实话。
but you definitely didn't tell the truth.
不是全部的真相。
Not the whole truth.
你告诉他们是我杀了那个女孩，但是…
I mean, you told them I killed that girl, but...
你没告诉他们我丈夫的事。
you didn't tell them about my husband.
我怀孕了。
That I was pregnant.
我只是想保护我未出生的孩子。
That I was just trying to protect my unborn child.
我不是去保护你的
I wasn't there to defend you.
那个女孩的名字叫莉齐·基尔缪尔。
And the girl's name was Lizzie Kilmuir.
一切都好吗?
Everything OK?
看不见你。
Aye.
我正要走。
I was just leaving.
呃,抱歉。你……
Er, sorry. You...
你不记得我了，是吗?
You don't remember me, do you?
圣诞节。肯定是2001 ?
Christmas. Must've been 2001?
你和你的醉鬼朋友在我在丹尼斯顿的公寓过夜。
You and your drunken pal spent the night in my flat in Dennistoun.
不，我觉得那不是我。
No, I don't think that was me.
“伯恩斯是完美的诗人，《大白鲨》是完美的电影。”
"Burns is the perfect poet and Jaws the perfect movie."
好的。也许那就是我。
OK. So maybe that was me.
你的醉友是马克·帕丁森。
Your drunken pal was Mark Pattison.
你当警察的时候，你和他在皮特街工作。
You and he worked out of Pitt Street when you were in uniform.
马克是我的兄弟。我是他的小妹妹。
Mark's my brother. I'm his wee sister.
正确的。马克·帕蒂森。
Right. Mark Pattison.
梅格,你。
And you're Meg.
看不见你。Dennistoun。是的，我现在想起来了。
Aye. Dennistoun. Yeah, I remember now.
-不，不，你不能。——我……
- No, no, you don't. - I'm...
好的,别担心。
OK, don't worry.
你喝醉了。有趣,但是喝醉了。
You were pretty drunk. Fun, but drunk.
好吧，我只能相信你的话了。
Well, I'm going to have to take your word for it.
呃，你是护士吗?
Er, and you're nursing?
啊哈。专门从事临终关怀。
Uh-huh. Specialising in end-of-life care.
那一定很艰难。
That must be tough.
奖励。
Rewarding, too.
你知道唐娜的过去吗
Are you aware of Donna's history?
我不是来做判断的。
I'm not here to make judgments.
正确的。好吧，有人会的。
Right. Well, there are people who will.
呃…
Er...
如果你遇到什么麻烦，给我打电话。
if you get any trouble, then give me a call.
我的号码在背面。
My number's on the back.
顺便说一句，你是对的。
Oh, and you were right, by the way.
这是一部完美的电影。
It is the perfect movie.
你是说SD卡?
An SD card, you say?
是的。我们认为戴高迪可能把它带在了潜水室里。
Yeah. We think Gauldie might have had it with him in the dive chamber.
他们刚把他的东西送来了。
Well, they've just brought his belongings in.
它们还在盒子里。我们还没来得及看一遍呢。
They're still in boxes. We've not had a chance to go through them yet.
-我很乐意帮忙。-不，你很好
- I'm happy to help. - No, you're all right.
我们将管理。
We'll manage.
-但这可能需要一些时间。-没问题。
- But it could take some time. - That's no problem.
我就在这里等着。
I'll just wait over here.
凯特。凯特，我知道这很难。
Kate. Kate, I know it's hard.
唐娜也不会待太久的，所以…
Look, Donna's not going to be around for long anyway, so...
你无缘无故地让自己心烦。
you're getting yourself upset for no reason.
没有理由吗?
No reason?
她杀了我妹妹。这是一个很大的原因。
She killed my sister. That's a big reason.
我不是那个意思。
I didn't mean it like that.
你当然有理由生气。
Of course you have every right to be angry.
愤怒还不足以掩盖它。
Angry doesn't even begin to cover it.
我知道。
I know.
我很抱歉发生了这样的事。
And I'm sorry this has happened.
你不配。
You don't deserve it.
听着，我得走了。
Look, I've got to go.
大便。
Shit.
吉米?
Jimmy?
你没事吧，爸爸?
You all right, Dad?
哦……一定是睡着了。
Oh... Must have fallen asleep.
今天的事我很抱歉。
I'm sorry about today.
今天好吗?
Today?
关于在斯卡洛威餐厅吃午饭时的混乱。
About the mix-up over lunch at The Scalloway.
-但邓肯带我去吃午饭了。-是的，我知道
- But Duncan took me to lunch. - Yes, I know that.
但之前，你以为我要…
But before, you thought that I was going to...
你和邓肯去哪了?
Where did you and Duncan go?
哦，在城里的某个地方。你妈妈会喜欢的。
Oh, somewhere in the town. Your mum would've liked it.
是,是。
Aye, aye.
噢,那是大。
Oh, that's grand.
-谢谢你照顾他。-哦，没问题。
- Thanks for looking after him. - Oh, no problem.
他状态很好。
He was on fine form.
你看起来需要喝一杯。
You look like you need a drink.
唐娜。
Donna's back.
你见过她吗?
You seen her?
她刚才在楼上的家里。
She's up at her house just now.
看起来她从没离开过。
Looks like she's never been away.
凯特和她的朋友们肯定会接受的。
Well, that'll go down well with Kate and her pals.
比利?
Billy?
弗洛拉不是人。这是一个地方。
Flora M isn't a person. It's a place.
弗洛拉·马里斯宗教静修所。
The Flora Maris religious retreat.
在沃尔塞结束了。他们和船主交谈。
It's over on Whalsay. They spoke to the ferry master.
他证实了加尔布雷斯死前一天在那里。
Who confirmed that Galbraith was over there the day before he died.
加尔布雷斯来宗教静修做什么?
What the hell's Galbraith doing at a religious retreat?
我不知道。
I have no idea.
但船长说这是他的常规行程。
But the ferry master said it was a regular trip for him.
好的。
OK.
嗨。
Hi.
我是吉米·佩雷斯探长。
I'm Detective Inspector Jimmy Perez.
我是来调查亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯的谋杀案的。和我……
I'm here investigating the murder of Alex Galbraith. And I'd...
哦,来吧!
Oh, come on!
-你什么时候回家的?-几个小时前
- When did you get home? - Couple of hours ago.
我打不开这些该死的文件。
Urgh, I can't open these bloody files.
什么文件?
What files?
我昨晚拿到了埃蒙·高迪的SD卡。
I picked up Eamon Gauldie's SD card last night.
我看到里面有视频文件。但就是打不开。
I can see there are video files on it. But they won't open.
你想让我……吗?
Do you want me to...?
啊,是的。看起来他们腐化了。
Aye, yeah. Looks like they're corrupted.
-那你能修好吗?——也许。
- Well, can you fix them? - Maybe.
我在局里有一些恢复软件。
I've got some recovery software at the station.
那你得过去一趟。你一打开就给我打电话。
Then you need to get over there. As soon as you open them, you call me.
-待会儿见。——再见。
- See you later. - See ya.
-唐尼!——我走了。
- Donnie! - I'm going.
你一定是佩雷斯局长。
You must be DI Perez.
我的妹妹卡罗琳。
I'm Sister Carolyn.
宝拉修女说你在调查亚历克斯的死。
Sister Paula said you were looking into Alex's death.
我在调查他的谋杀案。
I'm investigating his murder.
我还是不敢相信发生了这样的事。
Still can't believe it happened.
你知道他吗?
You knew him?
是的,…不。
Yes, and... no.
我们去散步好吗?
Shall we go for a walk?
亚历克斯十个月前开始来这里。
Alex started visiting about ten months ago.
我们把一些土地卖给了路边的农场。
We were selling some land to the farm up the road.
他负责法律方面的事务。
And he was taking care of the legal side.
然后呢，他一直回来吗?
And what, he just kept on coming back?
大多数情况下，他只会出现几个小时。我们喝茶，聊天。
He'd turn up most weeks for a few hours. We'd drink tea, talk.
-有什么特别的事吗?——他的生活。主要是。他的麻烦。
- About anything in particular? - His life. Mostly. His troubles.
所以你是他的心理医生?
What, so, you were his therapist?
我尽量不去评判。
I tried not to judge.
他赞赏。
He appreciated that.
我也不想问你这个，但是，
You know, I hate to have to ask you this, but,
你和他在一起吗?
were you and he together?
-就是睡在一起?-是的。
- As in sleeping together? - Yeah.
上帝,没有。
God, no.
你怎么会这么想?
What on Earth made you think that?
因为他女儿确信他怀了
Well, because his daughter was convinced that he was having
外遇。
an affair.
她无意中听到他给你打电话，所以她以为…
And she overheard him on the phone to you, so she assumed that...
我是他的姘头吗?
I was his bit on the side?
即使我有资格谈恋爱，
Even if I was in a position to be in a relationship,
我不会选择亚历克斯。恶魔太多了。
I wouldn't have chosen Alex. Far too many demons.
不过，如果他的生命中没有另一个女人，我会很惊讶。
Although, I'd be surprised if there wasn't another woman in his life.
别误会我的意思
You know, don't take this the wrong way
但你看起来不太像修女。
but you don't seem much like a nun.
因为我不是。
Cos I'm not.
宝拉修女和其他人都是真正的修女。
Sister Paula and the others are real nuns.
我就是他们所谓的生活专业人士。
I'm what they call life professed.
这意味着我祈祷，独处，行善，
It means I do the prayer, the solitude, the good deeds,
但我不参与"嫁给耶稣"那部分
but I sit out on the whole married to Jesus bit.
景色真不错，是吧?
It's quite a view, eh?
是的。我妈妈喜欢这里。
Yeah. My mum loves it up here.
爱。
Loved.
你最近失去她了?
You lost her recently?
——我很抱歉。-不，不用。
- I'm sorry. - No, don't be.
你还好吗?
How are you holding up?
呃，我还没有机会考虑这个问题。
Err, I've not really had a chance to think about it.
我要工作，还要照顾我爸爸。
I've got work and my Dad to look after.
但你必须为她哀悼。
But you have to mourn her.
我想我不想。
I don't think I want to.
我知道悲伤需要很长时间说实话我…
I know how long grief takes, and to be honest, I'm...
你是什么?
You're what?
我开始明白为什么亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯每周都来这里。
I'm beginning to understand why Alex Galbraith came here every week.
所以你在他死的前一天见过他。你觉得他怎么样?
So you saw him the day before he died. How did he seem to you?
一如既往的烦恼。
His usual troubled self.
但不为任何一件特别的事情烦恼?
But not troubled about any one thing in particular?
如果你是问他是否担心会被谋杀?然后,没有。
If you're asking if he was worried about being murdered? Then, no.
加尔布雷斯去看修女了?
Galbraith was seeing a nun?
不。她不是修女。
No. She's not exactly a nun.
但她也不是他的情妇。
But she's not his mistress, either.
尽管她说加尔布雷斯是那种
Although she did suggest that Galbraith was the type to
有另一个女人。
have another woman.
-缪尔的公寓搜查得怎么样了?——没有。
- How goes the search at Muir's flat? - Nothing yet.
但我昨晚找到了SD卡。
But I did find the SD card last night.
唐尼在局里，想打开文件。
Donnie's at the station trying to open the files.
-好的，我现在就去看他。——好的。
- Right, I'll go and see him now. - OK.
这到底是怎么回事?
What the hell's going on here?
-我不知道你和米克住在一起。——我不喜欢。
- I didn't realise you lived with Mick. - I don't.
他让我睡在沙发上
He lets me crash on the couch
当我们在工作之间遇到困难的时候。
when we've got a tight turn around between jobs.
这比住旅馆便宜多了。
It's a lot cheaper than a hotel.
我打电话给医院了
Oh, I called the hospital.
他们说他手术后正在恢复中。
They said he was recovering from surgery.
-嗯-他们给他的手臂复位了
- Mm. - They had to re-set his arm.
——耶稣。可怜的米克。-你知道是谁袭击了他吗?
- Jesus. Poor Mick. - Do you know who assaulted him?
-肯定是船员中的一员-但你不知道是哪一个?
- Had to be one of the crew. - But you don't know which one?
他们知道我和米克是朋友。所以他们最不可能告诉我的人。
They know I'm mates with Mick. So, I'm the last person they'd tell.
提醒你一下，我现在可以很容易地掐死米克。
Mind you, I could easily throttle Mick myself, right now.
为什么?
Why?
哦,来吧。
Oh, come on.
我是说，埃蒙出事一定是他造成的。
I mean, it had to have been him that caused Eamon's accident.
-你确定是意外?-还能是什么呢?
- You're sure it was an accident? - What else could it have been?
如果你睡在这里的沙发上，谁会睡在客房?
So if you sleep on the couch here, who sleeps in the guest room?
这是安琪拉的房间。米克的妹妹。
That's Angela's room. Mick's sister.
她和她的伴侣分手后，在这里住了几个月。
She stayed here for a few months, when she broke up with her partner.
她现在在戈尔斯皮。
She's in Golspie now.
卡上有四个视频文件。
There's four video files on the card.
第一个视频的时间是10点15分。最后一个是11:12。
Time stamp on the first video is 10:15. The last one is 11:12.
-是的，我想看最后一个。-这有点问题。
- Yeah, I want to see the last one. - There's a bit of a problem there.
卡肯定是在潜水事故中损坏的。
See, the card must've got corrupted during the dive accident.
因为文件打不开。
Cos the files won't open.
没有一个人吗?
None of them?
我整个早上都在运行恢复软件，但是，
I've been running recovery software all morning but the, err,
这些后来的文件都不见了。
these later files are gone.
我只能找到一段10点45分的录像。
Erm, all I could get was a bit of footage from a video timed 10:45.
但是上面有东西。
But there is something on it.
-那是Alex Galbraith的车——看这个。
- That's Alex Galbraith's car. - Watch this.
这就是我得到的全部信息。
So that's all I've managed to get.
另一辆车的登记信息太模糊了。
It's, it's too blurry to get a registration on the other car.
-但如果我做一些调整，我可以…-我知道这是谁的车。
- But if I do some tweaking, I can... - I know whose car it is.
-对，就是我。那又怎样?-那又怎样? !
- Yeah, that's me. So what? - So what?!
我们有一段录像显示你试图经营亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯的店
So, we've got video footage of you trying to run Alex Galbraith's
汽车驶离马路…
car off the road...
不，我不是想把他赶出马路。
No, I wasn't trying to run him of the road.
是在他被杀前半小时被枪杀的。
It was shot half an hour before he was killed.
所以你就在谋杀现场附近。
So that puts you in the vicinity of the murder scene.
-好吧，我杀了他?——妈妈。
- Oh, so well, I killed him, then?! - Mum.
没关系。我做了一件非常愚蠢的事。
It's OK. I did something really stupid.
我知道。但我很生气。
I know that. But I was angry.
我这几周一直想跟他说话，但一直不理我。
I'd been trying to talk to him for weeks, kept ignoring me.
-所以你撞了他的车?——不!我不是故意的，我…
- So you rammed his car? - No! I wasn't trying to, I...
老实说，我不知道我当时想做什么。我生气了。
Look, honestly, I don't know what I was trying to do. I just saw red.
他为什么不理你?
Why was he ignoring you?
对，因为他不想进入
Right, because he didnae want to get into
关于唐娜·基利克的争论
an argument about Donna Killick?
看看是不是，是不是某个来自南方的律师，
See if it was, if it was some lawyer from down south,
我就明白了。但他是从这里来的。
I would understand. But he was from here.
他知道把她带回来会带来痛苦。
He knew that bringing her back was going to cause pain.
但不管怎样，他还是做到了!
But he did it, anyway!
-之后发生了什么?——什么都没有。
- What happened after this? - Nothing.
我撞了他，吓了一跳，继续开车。
I hit him, I got a fright, I drove on.
-你没有跟踪他去他家?-我回家了。
- You didn't follow him to his house? - I came home.
她回来的时候我就在这里。
And I was here when she got back.
-那是什么时间?(约11。
- What time would that be? - About 11.
差不多和你在一起的时间
So, about the same time that you were with
弗雷泽·克雷根在他家?
Fraser Creggan at his house?
来吧,莫莉。你不能同时出现在两个地方。
Come on, Molly. You cannae be in two places at the one time.
你当时不是和弗雷泽在一起就是在这里。
Now, you were either with Fraser at his house or you were here.
到底是哪一个呢?
Now, which one is it?
我是一个人来的。
I was here on my own.
你认为凯特有能力吗?
Do you think Kate's capable?
六个月前，我会说不。
Six months ago, I'd have said no.
但现在，她看起来很生气。
But now, she just, she seems angry.
她和所有设得兰群岛的人。
Her and everyone else in Shetland.
搜查米克·缪尔的公寓。
The search of Mick Muir's flat.
-你找到什么了吗?-他和加尔布雷斯没有任何联系
- You manage to find anything? - Nothing linking him to Galbraith.
或者是戴高乐。
Or Gauldie, for that matter.
但凯莉·麦克安德鲁似乎认为是缪尔害死了高迪。
But Carrie McAndrew seems to think Muir caused Gauldie's death.
对不起。凯莉·麦克安德鲁是谁?
Sorry. Who's Carrie McAndrew?
她在潜水船上管理厨房。
She runs the kitchen on the dive ship.
-她在缪尔家做什么?-她在工作间隙呆在那里。
- What was she doing at Muir's? - She stays there between jobs.
但她不是唯一呆在那里的人。
But she's not the only one who stays there.
他给他妹妹准备了一张床
He's got a bed made up for his sister for
当她从戈尔斯皮回来的时候
when she's home from Golspie.
Golspie吗?
Golspie?
姐姐叫什么名字?
What's the sister's name?
老习惯,是吗?
Old habits, eh?
——什么?——你。
- What? - You.
在白天出现。偷偷摸摸。
Turning up during the day. Sneaking around.
带你回来。
Takes you back.
请注意,
Mind you,
如果你想要的是性，恐怕你会失望的。
if it's sex you're after, I'm afraid you might be disappointed.
-巨蟹座严重破坏性欲。-你为什么回来?
- Cancer plays havoc with the libido. - Why did you come back?
你惹的麻烦。你留下的烂摊子。这已经够糟糕的了。
The trouble you caused. The mess you left. That was bad enough.
-但是回来…-我有选择的
- But to come back... - I had a choice.
我要么死在牢房里，要么死在家里。
I either die in a cell or I die at home.
那其他人呢?
And what about everyone else?
操别人。
Fuck everyone else.
这是一个错误。
This was a mistake.
你也不是那么无辜，邓肯。
Y'know, you're not so innocent, Duncan.
你也需要为“混乱”承担一些责任。
You need to take some responsibility for "the mess" too.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我想保护的是你儿子。
It was your son I was trying to protect.
我所做的一切，只是为了保护艾伦的安全。
I only did, what I did, to keep Alan safe.
你知道如果凯文发现了他的事他会怎么做。
And you know what Kevin would've done if he'd found out about him.
你也该受到责备。
You are just as much to blame.
我没有杀了一个女孩然后让一个无辜的人在监狱里腐烂。
I didn't kill a girl and leave an innocent man to rot in prison.
不…不，你只是一如既往。
No... no, you just did what you always did.
表现得像个懦夫!
And played the bloody coward!
我都不知道他在哪儿!
Oh, I don't even know where he is!
艾伦吗?他在格拉斯哥。
Alan? He's in, he's in Glasgow.
-你和他有联系?——呃,没有。
- You're in contact with him? - Er, no.
凯西一直保持联系。老实说，他不想和我说话。
Cassie keeps in touch. To be honest, he doesn't want to talk to me.
我要见他。
I want to see him.
让他来看我，邓肯。
Make him come and see me, Duncan.
我不知道我能不能做到。
I don't know if I can.
在我死之前，我要再见我儿子一面。
I need to see my son again, before I die.
好的。谢谢。
OK. Thanks.
据凯莉说，缪尔的姐姐叫安吉拉。
According to Carrie, Muir's sister's name is Angela.
搬到戈尔斯皮之前，她和伴侣住在设得兰群岛，
Before moving to Golspie, she lived in Shetland with her partner,
和儿子。
and son.
搭档是洛根·克雷根。
Partner was Logan Creggan.
克雷根是缪尔的姐夫?
Creggan is Muir's brother-in-law?
Muir是Fraser的叔叔。
And Muir is Fraser's uncle.
所以洛根·克雷根杀了加尔布雷斯。
So Logan Creggan kills Galbraith.
-埃蒙·高迪看到或拍下了它。-不管怎样，他都是目击者
- Eamon Gauldie sees or films it. - Either way, he's a witness.
克雷根得照顾他。
Creggan has to take care of him.
克雷根打电话给缪尔，安排一场事故，并把它留在家里。
Creggan phones Muir to arrange an accident and keep it in the family.
时机会很紧迫。
The timing would be tight.
不过，这是可以做到的。
Could be done, though.
好的。在这儿等一下。
OK. Hold on a moment here.
昨天你还在说贩毒团伙和有组织犯罪。
Yesterday, you were talking about drug gangs and organised crime.
你是说那是一个前士兵和他的姐夫。
Now, you're saying it's an ex-squaddie and his brother-in-law.
不，昨天我们只是在找联系
No, yesterday we were looking for a connection
加尔布雷斯和高迪的谋杀案
between the killings of Galbraith and Gauldie.
射杀加尔布雷斯的人怎么可能
How could the person who shot Galbraith
乘潜水船去找高迪?这就是那种联系。
get to Gauldie on a dive boat? This here is, is that connection.
它们是相互关联的。那又怎样?
They're related to each other. So what?
这并不意味着有阴谋。你需要更多的证据。
It doesn't mean there's a conspiracy. You need more proof.
你爸爸在吗?
Is your Dad around?
-我得跟你谈谈，洛根。——所以,说话。
- Need to talk to you, Logan. - So, talk.
能告诉我这是怎么回事吗?
You want to tell me what this is about?
米克·穆尔。
Mick Muir.
关于他的什么?
What about him?
-你最后一次和他说话是什么时候?——我不知道。六个月前，也许吧。
- When did you last speak to him? - Dunno. Six months ago, maybe.
你确定最近没跟他联系过吗?
Are you sure you haven't been in contact with him more recently?
缪尔的电话记录显示他给这栋房子打了两次电话，
Muir's phone records show that he phoned this house twice,
埃蒙·高迪死的那晚
the night that Eamon Gauldie died.
埃蒙·高迪到底是谁?
Who the hell is Eamon Gauldie?
他是个潜水员，死在你姐夫的眼皮底下。
He's a diver who died on your brother-in-law's watch.
就是那个在加尔布雷斯家附近驾驶无人机的人，
Same guy who was flying a camera drone near Galbraith's house,
当他中枪的时候。
when HE was shot.
这些都是很有趣的东西
Well, this is all fascinating stuff -
这跟我有什么关系?
what's it got to do with me?
如果埃蒙·高迪是加尔布雷斯谋杀案的目击者，
If Eamon Gauldie was a witness to Galbraith's murder,
那他就成问题了。
then that would make him a problem.
凶手必须除掉他。
The murderer would have to get rid of him.
除了，埃蒙·高迪在海上。所以没办法接近他。
Except, Eamon Gauldie's at sea. So there's no way of getting to him.
除非他认识船上的人。
Unless he knows somebody on that ship.
现在，你明白我的意思了吗?
Now, do you see where I'm going with this?
耶稣。
Jesus.
你们真的快淹死了，嗯…
You lot are really drowning, eh...
我不知道这个高迪是谁但如果我真想让人杀了他，
I don't know who this Gauldie is but if I did want somebody to kill him,
我肯定不会去问米克·缪尔。他是个白痴。
I sure as shit wouldn't ask Mick Muir. The man's an idiot.
为什么亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯拒绝在IHAT案中为你辩护?
Why did Alex Galbraith refuse to represent you in the IHAT case?
-我告诉过你。我不知道。-也许他认为你有罪。
- I told you. I don't know. - Maybe he, he thought you were guilty.
他怎么想并不重要。
Well, it doesn't matter what he thought.
他仍然有责任保护我。
He still had a duty to defend me.
也许有一些案例
Maybe there were some cases that
就连亚历克斯·加尔布雷斯也无法忍受。
even Alex Galbraith couldn't stomach.
也许想到那些可怜的囚犯，你
Maybe the thought of those poor prisoners that you
你的朋友们把他打得屁滚滚打，把他赶走了。
and your pals beat the shit out of, repulsed him.
我想你现在最好离开。
I think you'd better leave, now.
好的。
OK.
胡说。
Tosh.
再给SPA打电话。
Call the SPA again.
我想知道更多关于这个死去的囚犯的事。
I wannae find out more about this prisoner who died.
我和水疗中心的联系人谈过了。
I spoke to my contact at the SPA.
克雷根被指控杀害的囚犯不是士兵。
The prisoner Creggan was accused of killing wasn't a soldier.
是个平民。一个十几岁的男孩。
It was a civilian. A teenage boy.
显然，克雷根的人抓住了他，把他带到山里去了。
Apparently, Creggan's unit captured him and took him into the hills.
他们把他打死了
And they beat him to death.
我一直在找你。现在…
I've been looking for you. Now...
你的朋友在哪里?
where is your friend?
我不明白你的意思。
I don't know what you mean.
快点。让他妈的。
Hurry up. Get fucking in.